Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（緑間）勝たせてもらうぞ 赤司
I'm going to win, Akashi.
That's impossible, Shintaro.
（赤司）それは無理だ 真太郎
Because I always win, I am always right.
すべてに勝つ僕は すべて正しい
He's fast!
（高尾(たかお)）速(はえ)え…
Nice pass!
（根武谷(ねぶや)）ナイスパス！
You're not going anywhere.
（宮地(みやじ)）させねえよ
（葉山(はやま)）３本でいいかな
Three should do it.
How is he dribbling like this?
（宮地）何だ？ このドリブル
My eyes can't keep up!
目で追えねえ
いや…
消えた？
It disappeared?
I Don't Know
（宮地）
チッ！ ったく んだこりゃ？
What is this?
I'm going to kill them all.
沈めんぞ どいつもこいつも
１年！
全然かかってねえよ モップ
First-years! You did a crap job mopping!
Don't slack off!
手ぇ抜いてんじゃねえよ
（１年生たち）ああ はい
Yes, sir!
（高尾）うへぇ
今日もキレてるよ 宮地さん
Miyaji-san's angry again today.
怖(こえ)ぇ…
So scary.
You, too!
（宮地）オメーらもだよ！
チンタラしてんじゃねえよ
Quit dragging your feet!
（高尾）うわぁ… うっす
Yes, sir!
（高尾）ああ 今日もキツかったわ
超キレられたし
Today was rough, too.
He was super pissed.
Miyaji-san's definitely the
scariest upperclassman.
ってか怖い先輩ダントツ１位だわ
宮地さんはマジで
What's up, Shin-chan?
どうした？ 真(しん)ちゃん
ハァ ハァ
（大坪(おおつぼ)）何やってんだ？
早く帰れよ オマエら
What are you doing?
Go home already.
あの… 大坪さん
Otsubo-san, I thought we weren't
テスト期間で
居残り練習 禁止なんじゃ…
supposed to stay late to practice
during testing periods.
（大坪）ああ 宮地か
Oh, you mean Miyaji?
Don't worry about him.
The coach gave him permission.
あいつはいいんだ
監督に許可もらってる
His grades are good.
成績いいからな
（高尾）いやぁ いっつも
怖いイメージしかなかったから—
I only ever thought of him as scary.
なんつーか 意外っスね
ああいうとこ見るの
Seeing that side of him was surprising.
Right. You guys don't know.
（大坪）
そうか オマエらは知らなかったか
I'm used to seeing it, though.
オレには見慣れた光景なんだがな
宮地は怖いか？
Does Miyaji scare you?
超怖いっスね
He's super scary.
He's made Shin-chan wet
himself a bunch of times.
真ちゃんとか
何度かチビってますからね
（緑間）チビってないのだよ
I haven't wet myself!
（大坪）まぁ 厳しいヤツだからな
He's a strict guy.
人にも 自分にも
On others and himself.
今まで 周りの何倍も
練習してきて—
He practiced more than
anyone else and finally
became a regular the summer
of his second year.
２年の夏に
ようやくレギュラー入り
スタメンに選ばれたのは
３年になってからだ
He didn't become a starter
until his third year.
It's not that he doesn't have talent.
決して才能がないわけじゃない
それでも—
But he made it this far through
backbreakingly hard work.
血のにじむような努力をして
ここまで来たのさ
Kimura's the same.
それは木村(きむら)も同様だ
だから誰よりもレギュラーである
自負と責任を感じているし—
That's why they feel the greatest pride
and responsibility of all the regulars
and why everyone trusts them.
周囲から信頼もされてる
He may be a little too strict on
you underclassmen, though.
オマエら後輩には
少し厳しいかもしれんが
それに あれで
なかなかいいところも…
Besides, there are some good things about...
あっ！ そうだ
Oh, right.
Midorima, this is from Miyaji.
緑間 これ宮地から
探してたろ？
明日の おは朝のラッキーアイテム
You were looking for this, right?
It's Oha Asa's lucky item for tomorrow.
アイドルうちわ
An idol fan.
（高尾）プッ！ 何それ？ おは朝？
What? Oha Asa?
クックッ…
アイドルうちわって
An idol fan?
ってかこれ
宮地さんの私物っスか？
Does this belong to Miyaji-san?
（大坪）ああ
あいつの推しメンだから みゆみゆ
Yeah, he's a fan of Miyu Miyu.
（高尾）ぐふっ… 推しメン…
A fan?
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
ちなみにオレは
まみりん派だ
Also, I'm a Mamiring fan.
８位のな
You know, in eighth.
（高尾）
マジっスか？ 大坪さんもっスか？
Seriously? You, too, Otsubo-san?
え？ お２人でコンサートとか
行ったりするんスか？
Do you guys do that crap together?
（大坪）ああ もちろんだ
Yeah.
（観客１）抜いた！
（観客２）すげードリブル
He passed him!
Such amazing dribbling!
（木村）このっ！
Damn it!
（木村）ダブルクラッチ！
A double clutch!
なんて身軽な野郎だ
He's so agile!
（観客１）決まったー！
（観客２）鮮やか！
He made the shot!
He's so good!
He passed two of Shutoku's defenders!
（観客３）
秀徳(しゅうとく)ディフェンス２人抜き！
（紫原）ていうか ドリブルうるさ
His dribbling is so loud.
（氷室(ひむろ)）ドリブルは強く
突いたほうがよいとされるが—
They say it's better to dribble harder,
but I've never seen anyone dribble that hard.
あそこまでのは初めて見るな
（氷室）それに… 何だ？
And why does his dribbling seem so strange?
あのドリブルには
何か違和感がある
Don't worry about it.
（大坪）
ドンマイ！ 切り替えろ
Let's switch gears.
Yeah.
Three should do it.
３本でいいかな？
（宮地）かろうじてだが 見えた
I barely saw it, but is that even possible?
けど まさか…
そんなこと できるのか？
Hayama only touched the ball
with three of his fingers.
今のドリブル—
葉山の指は
ボールに３本しか触れていなかった
そして３本ってのは—
"Three" meant the number of fingers
全身の力を
ボールに伝える指の本数のこと
he was using to convey his entire
body's strength to the ball.
Does that mean there are two
higher levels of that dribbling?
つまり 逆に言えば—
あのドリブルには
あと２段階 上がある
マジかよ！
Seriously?
Shutoku
Rakuzan
開いてきたね 点差
The gap's getting wider.
はっはっは！ ナイスパス！
Nice pass!
That hurt, you muscle-bound gorilla!
いってーな！ この筋肉ゴリラ！
Thanks!
おう！ サンキュー！
That's not a compliment!
ほめてねーよ
（高尾）クソッ！
Damn it!
こっちも真ちゃんいるから
何とか点は取れてるが—
We're managing to score with Shin-chan,
but the difference is too great.
内容が違いすぎんぜ
宮地さんだけじゃねぇ
大坪さんも完全にパワー負けしてる
Miyaji-san's not the only one.
They're completely overpowering
Otsubo-san, too.
They're leaving Kimura-san open
真ちゃんへのダブルチームで—
空いてるはずの木村さんも
苦しんでる
by double-teaming Shin-chan,
but he's struggling, too.
赤司はまだ何もしてない
Akashi hasn't done anything yet.
He's just passing effectively.
ただ有効な局面に
パスを入れてるだけ
それでも追いすがるのがやっとかよ
But we can barely keep up.
（実渕(みぶち)）要は あなた以外
足手まといってことよ 悪いけど
Sorry, but the rest of your
team is just holding you back.
What did you say?
何だと？
We're barely keeping you under
control by double-teaming you,
（実渕）確かにあなたは—
２人がかりで
抑えるのがやっとだけど—
but the other four are average at best.
あとの４人は 並かそれ以下
Especially him...
特に彼
How long do you think
he'll last against Kotaro?
小太郎(こたろう)を相手に
いつまで持つかしらね
Crap!
（高尾）しまった！
You're not going anywhere!
行かせねえ！
Weak!
甘いねえ！
（宮地）
クソッ！ クソッ！ クソッ！
Damn, damn, damn!
When did he...
（葉山）いつの間に？
うわぁ… 戻り速(はえ)え
He's so fast getting back!
Nice!
ナイス！
Holding me back?
（緑間）足手まとい？
What are you talking about?
何を言っているのだよ
A screen!
（実渕）スクリーン！
打たすかぁ！
You're not taking this shot!
このチームで足手まといなど—
I don't know of anyone who holds me back
オレは知らない
on this team.
（宮地）でやぁ！
He dunked it!
（観客１）おお！ ダンク出た！
（観客２）秀徳も負けてねぇ！
Shutoku's keeping up!
おう ナイスパス
Nice pass.
（紫原）ミドチン…
Midochin...
（観客１）来たー！
（観客２）高弾道スリー！
There it is!
The high trajectory three!
（大渕･木村･宮地）よーし！
Yeah!
Shutoku
Rakuzan
（根武谷）
さすがに一筋縄じゃいかねえな
Midorima Shintaro's not easy to handle.
緑間真太郎
どうする？ もう１人つけるか？
What should we do? Should
we put another man on him?
No, that's not necessary.
（赤司）いや 必要ない
これ以上の人数を割くのは
逆効果でしかない
Putting more men on him
would be counterproductive.
You may be Uncrowned Kings, but it will
be difficult for you to stop Shintaro now.
五将といえど 今の真太郎を
止めるのは難しいだろう
後半は１人でいい
We'll put one man on him in the second half.
What?
真太郎とは—
I will take on Shintaro.
僕がやろう
来たぞ
They're here.
The second game's teams are
warming up during the break.
インターバルは
第２試合出場チームのアップだ
You're not interested.
興味ないんだね
You seem to be doing all right.
（黄瀬）
調子 悪くないみたいっスね
フッ… どうかな
I'm not so sure.
赤司は まだ眼を
使っていないのだよ
Akashi hasn't used his eyes yet.
（緑間）
使ってくるとしたら 後半からだ
If he does use them, it will
be during the second half.
そこからが本当の勝負なのだよ
Then the true battle will begin.
Hey. I haven't seen you since
the opening ceremony, Tetsuya.
やあ 開会式以来だね
テツヤ
Yes, Akashi-kun.
（黒子(くろこ)）はい 赤司君
（日向(ひゅうが)）これが洛山(らくざん)
そして赤司征十郎か
This is Rakuzan and Akashi Seijuro...
They seem different from everyone else.
さすがに雰囲気 違(ちげ)えぜ
Hey. You haven't forgotten me, have you?
（火神(かがみ)）
よう まさか忘れてねーだろうな
You pulled some dangerous crap on me then.
あんときは随分
物騒なマネしてくれたな
I'll beat Kise, and I'll beat you.
黄瀬もオマエも 必ずぶっ倒す
Of course I remember you, Kagami Taiga.
（赤司）
もちろん覚えているよ 火神大我(たいが)
１つだけ 忠告しておこう
I should warn you.
Only those who serve me are
allowed to look me in the eye
僕と目線を変えずに話すことを
許しているのは—
when they speak to me.
僕に従う者だけだ
逆らう者は何人(なんぴと)たりとも
見下ろすことを許さない
I never allow those who oppose
me to look down at me.
Lower your head.
頭(ず)が高いぞ
What?
That wasn't strength!
（火神）力じゃねぇ…
今こいつ 何を？
What did he just do?
（日向）火神！
Kagami!
Kagami-kun!
（黒子）火神君！
（赤司）テツヤも—
Tetsuya.
If you intend to fight me,
you must prepare yourself.
僕とやるつもりなら
覚悟しておくことだ
I'm the one who discovered your power.
オマエの力を見出したのは僕だ
You will come to realize what that means.
いずれそれを思い知ることになる
見出した？ 黒子君の力を？
He discovered Kuroko-kun's power?
Yeah.
So his eyes allow him to
discover hidden powers in people?
（氷室）
眼っていうのは つまり—
人の隠れた才能を
見出す力のようなものか？
No.
まぁ 赤ちん
そういうのもすごいけど—
Akachin's good at that, too,
but it's different on the court.
試合でのは また別
すべてを無力にする
He makes everything powerless,
both offense and defense.
オフェンスもディフェンスも
そんな感じの力だよ
That's how his power works.
（紫原）すぐに分かるよ
You'll see soon enough.
Shutoku
Rakuzan
The second half is starting!
（観客）後半 始まったー！
I knew you would do this.
（緑間）やはりな
そう来ると思っていたのだよ
（赤司）来い 真太郎
Come, Shintaro.
（高尾）インターバル中
真ちゃんが予測してたけど—
This is what Shin-chan predicted during
the break, but are they serious?
マジかよ
（大坪）緑間 対 赤司
Midorima versus Akashi!
（氷室）いきなり勝負に来た
両チームエースのワンオンワン
They're challenging each other already.
It's a one-on-one with both teams' aces.
まず 間違いなく—
Whichever team wins this is sure
to take control of the game.
勝ったほうに流れが傾く
What?
（実渕）
ノーフェイクで いきなりスリー？
He's going for a three without a fake?
（氷室）バカな！
飛ぶ前にカットするなんて
Impossible!
I can't believe he intercepted
the ball before he jumped!
反応が早すぎる
His reactions are too fast!
He's not fast.
早いんじゃないよ 見えてるだけ
He just sees it.
What?
（紫原）赤ちんの眼は—
Akachin's eyes make both
offense and defense powerless.
オフェンスもディフェンスも
すべて無力にする
You're not passing me!
抜かすかよ！
Pass you? I don't need to.
（赤司）抜く？ そんな必要はない
You're going to move for me.
君が どくんだ
（高尾）なっ…！ 切り返し？
He did a crossover during
the second I was reacting!
オレが反応した瞬間に… ヤベェ
Crap!
I never allow those who oppose
me to look down at me.
（赤司）逆らう者は何人たりとも
見下ろすことを許さない
頭が高いぞ
Lower your head.
（紫原）あの眼の前では
すべての動きは先を読まれる
He can predict every movement
with his eyes.
あらゆる技は封殺され
立っていることすら許されない
All abilities are rendered useless.
People can't even remain standing.
赤司征十郎には
相手の動きの未来が見える
Akashi Seijuro can predict the
future movements of his opponents.
Shutoku
Rakuzan
（笠松(かさまつ)）秀徳が14点ビハインド？
Shutoku is fourteen points behind?
（火神）
ハーフタイムまで同点だったのに
They were tied at halftime.
What? He dodged it?
（木村）かわしただと？
He was in his blind spot!
（宮地）
今 完全に死角だったろうが！
あいつの眼は
ホークアイ並の視野もあんのかよ
Do his eyes give him the same
field of vision as the Hawk Eye's?
It's no use. I can't get
into a shooting stance.
（緑間）
ダメだ シュート体勢に入れない
He intercepts the ball the second
he starts to shoot or dribble.
（高尾）シュートもドリブルも—
あらゆるモーションに
入った瞬間 カットされる
Shin-chan can't move a single step!
あの真ちゃんが
マジで一歩も動けねぇ
Hey!
（高尾）ヘイ！
He even saw through that pass fake?
（大坪）
あのパスフェイクも見抜くのか
（笠松）トリプルスレット
The triple threat.
The most basic form in basketball.
バスケットにおける
最も基本となる姿勢
The stance sets up shooting,
passing, and dribbling.
シュート パス ドリブル
すべての動作に備えた状態のことだ
No matter how quick someone
is, just before he moves,
バスケット選手は
どんなに速く動いていても—
次の動作の直前
一瞬 その姿勢に入ってる
he always enters the corresponding form.
Akashicchi's future-predicting
eyes never miss that moment.
赤司っちの先を見る眼は
その一瞬を逃さない
No one can even move in
the face of his defense.
あのディフェンスの前では
動くことすら許されない
Not even fakes work against him.
たとえそれが フェイクであっても
You're not going anywhere!
（宮地）行かせるか！
Why don't you get out of my way?
（赤司）どいてもらおうか
You can't seriously think we'll do that!
“はい そうですか”
なんて言うわけねーだろ！
Don't get ahead of yourself, first-year!
調子 乗んなよ！ １年坊主
（赤司）
いいや 僕の命令は絶対だ
No. My orders are absolute.
（木村）
どうなってんだ？ クソッ！
What's going on? Damn it!
We can't even stay on our feet!
（宮地）
立ってることすら できねえだと？
What was that?
（氷室）
どういうことなんだ？ あれは
（紫原）アンクルブレイク
An ankle break.
高い技術を持つ
高速ドリブラーが—
Skilled high-speed dribblers
use that technique
相手の足を崩して
転ばせるテクニックだよ
to throw their opponents off
balance and make them fall.
相手の軸足に重心が乗った瞬間に
切り返したときのみ—
The technique can only be performed when
your opponent's center of gravity is
on his pivot leg while he's turning.
起こせる現象
先が見える赤司っちの眼は
それを たやすく引き起こす
For Akashicchi and his
future-predicting eyes, it's easy.
Is he passing behind his back?
（大坪）ビハインドパスか！
ヒジで逆サイドにパスだと？
He passed to the other side with his elbow?
（根武谷）ナイスパス！
Nice pass!
よっしゃー！
Yeah!
Emperor Eye.
（紫原）エンペラーアイ
As long as he has those eyes,
あの眼があるかぎり
赤ちんが負けることは—
少なくともオレには考えらんないな
I can't imagine Akachin losing.
He's crushing Shutoku like they're children.
（火神）秀徳が まるで子供扱い
This is Akashi Seijuro.
これが赤司征十郎
Damn it.
（高尾）クソッ！
こうなったらオレが直接…
I'll just have to...
ちょっと
Hey, don't forget about us!
私らのことも
忘れてもらっちゃ困るわよ
Akashi!
赤司！
Shintaro, you are strong.
真太郎 オマエは強い
But you will lose.
だが 負ける
“キセキの世代”を従えていたのは
誰だと思っている？
Who do you think commanded
the Generation of Miracles?
Not even you can stand against me.
（赤司）たとえ オマエたちでも
僕に逆らうことなど できはしない
Shutoku
Rakuzan
A 20 point difference...
（リコ）20点差…
This is the true strength
of Rakuzan and Akashi.
（日向）これが洛山
そして赤司の実力か
Come on, Shin-chan.
ほら
真ちゃん
How long are you going to keep sitting there?
いつまで座ってんだ バカ
メガネ 割んぞ
I'll break your glasses!
（木村）おい！
Hey!
あの字が見えねえのか？
Can't you see those characters?
シャキッとしろや！
Pull yourself together!
Indomitable
Make the shot, Midorima!
（秀徳部員１）
決めてくれー！ 緑間！
Go get them, Miyaji!
（秀徳部員２）宮地！
（秀徳部員３）行けー 高尾！
Go, Takao!
Midorima, Takao. We still have time.
緑間 高尾
まだ時間はある
最後まで諦めるな！
まずは１本だ
Don't give up before the game's over.
Let's get a basket.
Let's go win.
勝ちに行くぞ
Hey, Shin-chan.
（高尾）なあ 真ちゃん
Miyaji-san was really scary
during practice, wasn't he?
宮地さんってホント怖かったよな
練習中
Yes.
（緑間）そうだな
Otsubo-san was serious and strict, too.
（高尾）大坪さんも
真面目で厳しい人だったし—
ただでさえキツイ練習に
一切 手抜きなし
Practice was hard enough already,
but they never let anyone relax.
I thought I would die
during our training camp.
合宿とか 死ぬかと思ったし
I puked a bunch of times.
何度も吐いてさぁ
But the watermelon Kimura-san
brought us was really good.
ああ でも—
木村さんの差し入れのスイカは
マジでうまかったなぁ
（緑間）そうだな
Yes.
The more I think about it,
（高尾）思い返せば返すほど—
ホントつくづく—
the more I wish
we could keep playing basketball with them.
あの人たちと
もっとバスケ やっててえな
そうだな
Yes.
The game isn't over yet.
（黒子）まだ勝負は分かりません
Because Midorima-kun and
his team haven't given up.
（黒子）なぜなら—
緑間君たちは
まだ諦めていません
Let's go, Takao.
（緑間）行くぞ 高尾
（高尾）おうよ
Sure thing.
とっておきを—
Let's show them
見せてやる
what we have up our sleeves!
Preview
（高尾）やっぱ 強(つえ)えわ 洛山
Rakuzan is strong.
No one can deny it.
（緑間）認めざるを得ないのだよ
But the game's just getting started.
（高尾）でも勝負はこれからだ！
（緑間）当然なのだよ
Of course. Are you ready, Takao?
準備はいいか？ 高尾
I Will Give Them to You
Yeah.
（高尾）ああ 絶対 オマエに
シュートを決めさせてやるぜ！
I'll make sure you can make
your shots, Shin-chan!
真ちゃん！